# **Raven Hughes**

 $\underline{\text{ravenhillh@gmail.com } \text{I } \underline{\text{github.com/ravenhillh}} \text{ I } \underline{\text{linkedin.com/in/ravenhillh}} \text{ I } \underline{\text{www.ravenhillhughes.com}}$ 

(206) 992-3206 | New Orleans, LA

#### PERSONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled and motivated Full Stack Engineer with a passion for building creative and efficient applications, accomplished in Elixir, Phoenix, JavaScript, React, and SQL. Proven track record of designing and implementing complex applications with a focus on user experience and simplicity.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Revelry** / Software Engineer Apprentice

#### September 2024 - December 2024

- Contributed to a complex multi-repo project using Javascript, Typescript, React and Redux for an enterprise video review and collaboration platform
- Worked tickets in an Elixir back-end using Phoenix, Ecto and Postgres
- Operated as part of a team using Agile practices such as Retros, Kickoffs and Planning Poker

#### La Boulangerie / Baker

#### March 2021 - November 2023

Mixed, shaped and baked a variety of doughs, breads and pastries, taking care and attention to detail to produce the
finest products, and coordinated with all restaurant staff to guarantee that products were ready and on schedule for
customers and deliveries, organized workflows, and trained incoming bakery employees

# Arthur Ashe Charter School / Teacher

July 2015 - May 2016

- Developed and implemented engaging and rigorous lesson plans
- Analyzed student work to effectively assess learning and respond to data
- Collaborated with other teachers and administrators to create a positive academic and cultural environment

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Elixir
- Frontend: React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, Phoenix
- Backend: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, MySQL, Sequelize, Mongoose
- Tools & Technologies: Git, GitHub Actions, RESTful APIs, Webpack, Socket.IO, Grunt.js
- Additional: Agile/Scrum methodologies, Testing frameworks (Mocha/Chai), CI/CD

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Gallivant | Map-based tour taking and creation app ht

https://github.com/ravenhillh/Gallivant

- Designed and developed a real-time chat feature using Socket.IO
- Implemented interactive maps with geolocation and popups using MapBox APIs
- Utilized Sequelize and MySQL to design complex schemas and ensure efficient data storage
- Employed Typescript for robust error handling
- Deployed application using AWS EC2 instance

## Dogagatchi 2.0 | Virtual Pet collection and trivia app

https://github.com/ravenhillh/dogagatchi

- Engineered a blog feature that interacts with OpenAl API, providing users with personalized narratives
- Utilized React Hooks to create functional components and React Bootstrap for responsive UI design
- Managed a MongoDB Atlas database using Mongoose for seamless data storage and retrieval

## Gallerist | Art-sharing and social media app

https://github.com/ravenhillh/gallerist

- Employed Git workflow to implement clean and easy interaction between team repos
- Designed routing using Express to facilitate data transfer between the client, server, and NoSQL database
- Integrated Passport and Google OAuth for secure user authentication

# **EDUCATION**

# **Operation Spark**

2023 - 2024

- Program: Advanced Software Engineering Immersive Program
- Certificate: IBC Fundamentals of Javascript, Functional Programming and Web Development Level 3

## **University of New Orleans**

2009 - 2014

- Program: Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Secondary Education
- Certificate: Louisiana State Teaching Certificate